Some people have said aging is more a slide into forgetfulness than a journey towards wisdom.
有人曾说，衰老与其说是一段走向智慧的旅程，不如说是一路滑向健忘。
However, a growing body of research suggests that late-in-life learning is possible.
然而，越来越多的研究表明，晚年学习是有可能的。
In reality, education does an aging brain good.
实际上，教育对日渐衰老的大脑有益。
Throughout life, people’s brains constantly renovate themselves.
人的大脑一生都在不断地自我更新。
In the late 1960s, British brain scientist Geoffrey Raisman spied growth in damaged brain regions of rats through an electron microscope; their brains were forging new connections.
20世纪60年代末，英国脑科学家杰弗里·雷斯曼通过电子显微镜观察到，大鼠受损的脑区在生长；它们的大脑正在建立新的连接。
This meant brains may change every time a person learns something new.
这意味着，人每学到一样新东西，大脑都可能发生变化。
Of course, that doesn’t mean the brain isn’t affected by time.
当然，这并不意味着大脑不受时间的影响。
Just as height usually declines over the years, so does brain volume: Humans lose about 4 percent every decade starting in their 40s.
正如身高通常会随着岁月流逝而下降，脑容量也是如此：人从40多岁开始，脑容量每十年会减少约4%。
But that reduction doesn’t necessarily make people think slower; as long as we are alive and functioning, we can alter our brains with new information and experiences.
但这种减少并不一定会让人思考得更慢；只要我们还活着、机能正常，就能用新的信息和经历改变自己的大脑。
In fact, scientists now suspect accumulating novel experiences, facts, and skills can keep people’s minds more flexible.
事实上，科学家现在推测，积累新奇的经历、知识和技能，可以让人的头脑保持得更加灵活。
New pathways can strengthen our ever-changing mental structure, even as the brain shrinks.
即使在大脑萎缩之际，新的通路也能强化我们不断变化的心智结构。
Conventional fixes like word puzzles and brain-training apps can contribute to mental durability.
像文字谜题和脑力训练应用这样的常规办法，都有助于增强心智的持久力。
Even something as simple as taking a different route to the grocery store or going somewhere new on vacation can keep the brain healthy.
哪怕只是换一条路线去杂货店，或者度假时去一个没去过的地方，这样简单的事也能让大脑保持健康。
A desire for new life challenges can further boost brainpower.
对人生新挑战的渴望能进一步增强脑力。
Research about aging adults who take on new enterprises shows improved function and memory as well as a reduced risk of mental disease.
有研究以上了年纪、着手新事业的成年人为对象，结果显示，他们的机能和记忆力都有所改善，患精神疾病的风险也有所降低。
Openness—a characteristic defined by curiosity and a desire for knowledge—may also help folks pass brain tests.
开放性——一种以好奇心和求知欲为标志的特质——也可能有助于人们通过脑力测试。
Some folks are born with this take-in-the-world attitude, but those who aren’t as genetically gifted aren’t necessarily out of luck.
有些人天生就有这种乐于接纳世界的心态，但那些在基因上没那么得天独厚的人，也未必就没有指望。
While genes can encourage an interest in doing new things, a 2012 study in the journal Psychology and Aging found completing reasoning tasks like puzzles and number games can enhance that desire for novel experiences, which can, in turn, refresh the brain.
虽然基因可以激发人们做新鲜事的兴趣，但2012年发表在《心理学与老龄化》期刊上的一项研究发现，完成谜题、数字游戏之类的推理任务，可以增强对新奇经历的那种渴望，而这种渴望反过来又能让大脑重焕活力。
That’s why brain scientist Richard Kennedy says, “It’s not that old dogs can’t learn new tricks.
这就是为什么脑科学家理查德·肯尼迪会说：“并不是老狗学不会新把戏。
It’s that maybe old dogs don’t realize why they should.”
而是老狗或许没有意识到自己为什么应该去学。”